<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Workshops | Clara Saito - Performance and Visual Artist</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/teaching/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/teaching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Workshops</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/media/logo.svg</url>
      <title>Workshops</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/teaching/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theater of Drag</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/teaching/theatre-of-drag/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/teaching/theatre-of-drag/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Theater of Drag workshop by Clara Saito organized by 
 at the Rietveld Academie and Sandberg Institute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The workshop invited people to explore using performance and theater as a transformative and political way of expressing and acting upon struggles, all of it in drag. It was informed by the Theatre of the Oppressed, a community-based technique developed by Augusto Boal. The workshop included creating characters, expressing our emotions, performing for each other, and having discussions about the struggles we face in everyday life, using humor and over-dramatization in the style of telenovelas.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Tropical - Part 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/teaching/gettingtropical/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/teaching/gettingtropical/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Getting Tropical - Part 2 at 
 is a performance Workshop: &lt;br&gt;SHAKE YOUR STEREOTYPE AWAY.&lt;br&gt; performance arts – feminism – social sciences – artivism&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the performative and movement practices we research in the piece Getting Tropical we have the practices of cracks: strategies to move within the gaps of colonial and institutional projects. A translation for what philosopher and babalorixá Luiz Simas calls &amp;ldquo;Brasilidade&amp;rdquo;. We practice within our daily lives and studios some of them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;transgressive practices of reinvention
false domestication
re-enchantment
disobedience
working with the unknown
disidentifications&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
